all right and we are back it
is jack murphy live this is jack murphy
you can find me on twitter at jack
murphy live the website is
jackmurphylive.com
the book is democrat to deplorable go
and get one on amazon
right now why nine million obama voters
ditch the democrats and embrace donald
trump in 2016.
we'll also tell you why even more are
going to do the same
in 2020 silent majority grows and they
will
be heard in november no doubt also
if you're into masculinity sovereignty
and brotherhood come down and check out
the liminal order
liminal hyphen order dot com sign up for
the wait list there my guest today is
somebody that i have wanted to talk to
for a long time
and uh we've had ongoing dm
conversations and all kinds of stuff so
it's great to see you i've got daver boy
here
dave how are you i am fine it's great to
be here
with you finally yeah it's awesome dave
is a veteran national security and
political communications consultant
he's from the new york city area you can
find him on twitter at
dave roboy he's also a clermont fellow
i've noticed i keep having a number of
the claremont guys on it's almost as if
you guys have got a good thing going on
over there
i appreciate that and then dave also has
a couple of books coming up one's going
to be on cotter and on
russia gate but all from the perspective
of information operations which is
something
we're going to talk about today and
we're also going to talk about the
middle east
like what is going on over there it's
like mind blowing trump's getting nobel
peace prize nominations left and right
and it seems like a pretty historic
moment so we're going to get into that
but first
i want to learn a little bit about daver
boy because i
first of all love getting to know people
and two it's really important to put
the context around the speaker and i
think that makes for a more holistic
conversation so dave
give us a little bit of background man
how did you get to where you are what
are you doing who are you what's going
on dave
what's going on so so the story begins
um
i guess uh around the time that my
parents my family came
to the united states from uh
from communist romania in the 1960s both
came around a time and i grew up with a
very strong
um anti-communist perspective
and i was very involved in uh you know
my my uh
my grandfather was an auschwitz survivor
uh we lost
uh much of the family there and
they had he had very
uh bravely stood up against the
communist regime
and he left he was he was in the black
market
over there and and he brought his family
here with
with absolutely nothing so he gave away
every material possession
that uh that he had in order for
you know for um for a hundred dollars in
cash
from jewish family services and uh you
know and and
and the ticket to uh to come to the us
so he was a big he was a big
um uh he was a big
let's say anti-communist and um uh
reagan democrat would be that would be
the the good word to uh
to use so i grew up always knowing that
there
is totalitarianism in the world and
there is you know this thing that we may
call evil
um but
i guess the biggest point is that people
really believe
things that are bad
and it's not a mistake it's not
um uh it's not uh
you know it's it's people believe things
that have totalitarian consequences and
then it happens all the time it happened
in world war ii and it happened after
world war
ii uh uh under the uh under the iron
curtain
so they came here i grew up with that
kind of very strong
um perspective
yeah let me ask a question about that
for a second evil
right uh it seems to me that there is a
divide
right now between people that accept
evil exists
and believe something needs to be done
about it and people who are just sort of
blind to evil
in the world and kind of pretend that it
doesn't exist do you see this sort of
dichotomy is there a disconnection
current you know contemporary american
politics from
truly understanding history and what's
out there in the world
yeah i mean maybe i shouldn't have used
the word because
the word conjures up uh kind of uh
religiosity
necessarily and what we see on the left
too is we see
very very very strong religiosity it's
just
you know secularized religiosity again
every every
uh totalitarian system will have you're
not going to rid the world or raid
human beings the impulse for the sacred
whatever that
you know happens to mean at the time so
um
so i think i think there is a very
strong people have made the case
that kind of wokeness is um a
a revival of the puritanical
spirit of america just kind of
repurposed and i think there's there's
you know some some truth to that uh
people will always have the
um people will always have objects of
hatred
um whether religious or or ideological
or something
there's there's a reason why the world
sucks
and you know and and you know we blame x
for that so
so i i think i think the the religious
impulse for let's say that
the impulse to identify evil is very
very strong i mean we see it in
critical theory people say evil is
whiteness
so it's not much different than um
you know it's it's it's not much
different than uh
than kind of religious impulses through
the uh
through the use i like your phrase the
impulse for the sacred
that that is there and and i've seen uh
that
uh brought up in the conversation of
like what happens
when religion retreats from mainstream
society
what fills what comes in behind it
right it really could be anything i mean
that was chesterton right who
um who talked about uh you know the
retreat of religion
and and you know leaving a you know kind
of leaving a hole that is replaced by
something else and that's something else
is uh
that something else is almost always a
kind of statism
or you know a kind of paganism so
so that's what we're seeing and i say
that as a completely irreligious person
uh i know i have a lot of friends that
are kind of on both sides of the
spectrum but i just
you know from from a personal belief
standpoint i've never had it
um and i've never been able to really
relate to it but i
am very i i very much see the importance
of
uh a framework a kind of civilizational
framework of belief
for people because you know the the the
world can't handle
uh being divorced from some of these
concepts
yeah i feel that i feel the same thing i
mean i was bar mitzvahed
and went to church catholic mass i'm
half irish half uh
half irish catholic half jewish and um
i too sort of have felt a there's a i
think there's almost a void
actually you know i have more respect
every day for people who adhere to their
religious beliefs
uh and i do uh have a greater
appreciation for the value that that has
brought to
american society in particular and you
know at least maybe it's in
our circles but i do feel like there is
a growing revival perhaps
or at least an appreciation for the
benefits that come from
a society that is ordered in that
fashion and i think it's uh
important also to point out that like
america is really built on christian
values and so it's like
this is actually a christian country or
a religious country even if it's you
know technically separated church and
state so
interesting interesting phrase impulse
for the sacred you can see
it in their eyes when you're down in the
riots and in the protests and
i remember you know these riots lately
have been crazy but
i will never forget the kavanaugh
supreme court
protest where i was down there on the
steps of the supreme court
and there was just like thousands of
people just swarming the supreme court
and like banging on the doors and like
the chanting and the drums and this like
they were
like possessed you know like people
shaking and and
quivering and crying and just overcome
and uh
you know you can see that it it really
is sort of uh
religious in its impact in in sort of
not a pleasant way yeah
uh and uh it's something that we're
gonna have to struggle with um
moving forward i saw this at um
when i lived in uh i i guess you know
skipping a little head in
a little bit ahead in the biography um
or maybe we should just
just just uh finish that yeah so
so um i went to gw
to study um to study cold war history
marxism leninism
and totalitarian ideologies um
russia and eastern european
concentration that was very interesting
to me but it came at a time in the
in the mid 90s when we were really
you know the the most cutting edge of
of uh of political thought at that time
was thomas friedman you know the lexus
and the olive trees and
we're just going to solve every problem
here with um with globalism
we're going to flat yeah yeah exactly
and and i'm looking around and i'm
taking international affairs
uh international law classes and i said
this whole con this
this whole premise is a joke and
and i was the odd man out at the time
because i didn't i
i didn't see that that we're in kumbaya
mode forever
and um and i had um i had
i graduated gw with that degree and
it completely disillusioned me to um uh
to to working in politics because i i
really i thought i was surrounded by
by zombies i thought i was surrounded by
zombies in the national security space
um i was translating documents at uh
with what ended up
you know kind of unbeknownst to me at
the time turning out to be a very
uh left-wing outfit which was the
national security archive
and it was uh it was housed at gw and
the
the idea was to to uh to translate and
to classify
um uh
formerly um you know formerly classified
cold war documents so
i set out to work translating hungarian
1956 revolution um diplomatic cables and
things like that
from hungarian to english so so i was
doing that and i kept my head down and i
was thinking
to myself i have no idea how to fit
myself into this space
and i'm not sure what i'm going to do at
the same time of course i fall in love
with jazz and i begin playing music
and um and i kind of see that
as as uh the path that my life would
take so i
i moved to san francisco and then to new
york city and then back to san francisco
um all the while playing playing music
deeply um
uh deeply involved in the um in the the
avant-garde
uh and and free improvised uh music
scene in in
in those cities um at the same time
though i always had my politics i was
never a left-winger
and i would always go and uh do counter
protests
um i remember the first time i was
politically really politically
involved on my own one of these protests
was um
was in order to support the um
uh the danish embassy in i think
2005 there was a protest
outside uh the danish consulate in san
francisco
to support them for for publishing uh
the the muhammad cartoons
right and at that at that time um
this we we believe that this was a very
big
um step towards you know toward towards
freedom i mean you should be able to
mock muhammad you should the same way
you should be able to mock
um any other religious figure um if not
then you get into a blasphemy situation
right and
uh so so when they published those
cartoons we were supportive and of
course we were met with
with at that time counter protesters
from san francisco which is
you know straight up hamas and hezbollah
people
mixed in together with with you know far
leftists
and um and then i became very
politically involved after that
and and uh at a certain point i realized
that i should
i should make it my career because i'm
spending more time
uh you know i'm spending more time
reading um
reading you know islamic books than i am
um you know working to book gigs in town
so i thought it was uh it was a
reasonable thing and
you know it's it's hard to uh it's hard
to make a living and to live a life
when you're you know playing what is
really kind of commercially
marginal music and uh even though i love
it
and i still love it and i give all props
to people who make that
their their kind of life path knowing
what
all the struggle that entails i just
realized it was not for me
and um doing jazz is like being a or
being a professional jazz musician's
like being a professional poet
right you know there's not there's not a
giant market for it but yet it's still
high art and we
and we need it so it's uh right and i
knew i knew plenty professional poets as
well and
and you know you know if you think
that's if you think playing jazz is is
is hard imagine being a professional
poet
or a professional modern dancer or you
know
something something like that and and um
i mean those people really sacrifice and
they go and they're you know 65 years
old and they're waiting tables
right um and they may have lived
um or may you know still live a
wonderful fantastic rewarding life but
it's always going to be at the margins
yeah and
and now these and in those days it was
sort of possible to live on the margins
um i know this isn't a talk about
gentrification but uh it was possible
then
in the 90s the early 2000s to live in
the big city on the margins
you know you work what what like what i
used to do i used to work at a law firm
uh doing temp work for a week every
month
you know that gig would end but really a
week's worth of work was all that i
needed to pay my bills
in new york city at that time yeah man
today same experience living
in d.c living in dc in the 90s on the
edge of town
the cheapest place i could find and then
spending all of my time
doing dance parties that's what i did in
the 90s we did
technorave dance parties and warehouses
and i dj'd for years and that was
that was an interesting twilight space
to operate in there like on the fringes
but like still with one ear and the sort
of real world but then also in this
creative space
and you know that creative underground i
think is important and i wonder where
that
is today honestly if if there's any such
thing as because back then we thought we
were dissident right
right you know artists and dissident
creatives and
and we were i i just wonder is there a
dissident art
you know scene anywhere right now it
seems to me that all the
creative art and the art fringes are
really just rehashing and regurgitating
sort of the party lines these days
yeah i mean that's how it seems i'm sure
that there is uh i'm sure that there's
uh a kind of vibrant underground scene
that maybe we don't know about
um but it's all changed you know the
internet you know as
you know better than anybody the
internet has made a lot of things
possible that
um that were not previously possible
um it's closed a lot of doors but it's
also opened a lot of doors as well so
you don't necessarily need to be in a
in approximate physical space you know
you don't
you don't all need to live in this
village or or you know in in park slope
within three or four blocks of one
another
in order to create a scene that's that's
viable
um but on the other but on the other
hand
there's something really special about
creating that scene that's viable
within a couple of blocks of one another
everybody's sort of in there doing the
same thing
and and being together all day either at
the coffee shop
or you walk to it you know i mean when i
lived in new york
on the on the jazz scene i would see
let's say the 700 people
many many times a day walking here
walking there in in in
restaurants here in uh you know in
coffee shops
just just in the park and that did
create a sense of community
um that that um that was that was
special now of course nobody can afford
it
right but so so so
so jumping back i i i read a book
in um in in 2007
that ended up changing the direction of
my life
and uh and that was uh uh bloom closing
of the american mind
and uh you know i mean at the time i
didn't know
you know he very slyly never uses the
word you know uses the words leo strauss
but
um but the more you know
uh i mean that that was actually wise
and smart
i think from his perspective because
because you know why get bogged down
with
the whole intellectual history why not
present you know
make the case which he he really did
um on his own in a in a unique way
can you can you summarize the case i
mean this is a very powerful and
important book and everybody should
really read it and
it gets cited and referred to all the
time so
what what what was the main takeaway
from closing the american mind
so the main takeaway for the main
takeaway it's it's such a big book in
terms of of
of the different strands that uh that
dealt with and and just what i got from
it is
is is it's it's kind of really hard to
distill down but
af the first time i first time i read it
i said okay
this is wonderful i'm gonna start again
from chapter one
and after um after three or four
different uh you know different readings
you know very very close readings i
thought okay i kind of have
have the idea of what is what it what is
what is he saying that's important and
what is he saying that
that you know what are the most
important things he's trying to say so
for example
he's got all this misdirection in the
book about rock music
and about you know some of the things
that that i think people
will will kind of pop off and uh and
and uh and and freak out about and you
know i think the whole point of the book
too is kind of like a mcguffin
which is um it's supposed to be about uh
higher education but it's really not
about higher education
it is but it isn't you know it's about
um how the things that kind of rule our
lives
and the things that uh that put
civilization on a path and and define
what what we have here in terms of
regime at the end of the day are ideas
and his big concept was
that we are now living through the
consequences
of a particular set of ideas a
particular kind of anti-enlightenment
set of ideas
and um and and he you know he uh he he
traces the lineage
and um so he makes that point the other
point that he made
that i i thought was was kind of very
fascinating
was that um was that on one hand he he
breaks down
how
how the um how do you
best phrase it the uh
on one hand we want interdirected people
we say we want directed people and on
the other hand
we admire outer direct people now that's
a whole other
um that's a you know that's a whole
other ball of wax but
um i ended up reading the book and i and
and i thought you know what i really
need to start fighting
and i need to get in the game and uh and
i need to um
uh you know because this is this is kind
of the world the universe that i want to
deal with
and i want to dive in deeper and and i
ended up you know of course diving in
deeper and going from
from book to book and and from kind of
student of straus to student of strauss
you know in in uh in a kind of uh you
know concentric circle
and um and then i came to dc
and i said i you know i was always
fascinated with the national security
um uh perspective and the
thing that i really the other thing that
um
that you know obviously he got from from
strauss that was very important to me
was that um at the end of the day
historicism is the enemy so we can we
cannot bring
our modern um kind of uh
you know uh our modern [ __ ]
uh concepts of
you know our modern values to to uh you
know to the ancients and not only to the
ancients but
even to to you know people in prior eras
so it's not it doesn't make sense to
read
um you know it doesn't make sense to
read uh the founding fathers using
marxist analysis
um and think that it that it is
necessarily valid
i mean it could be interesting but it's
not necessarily valid and it doesn't get
to
to at the end it doesn't get the truth
so
i recognize this too from the
perspective of music
and and immediately and it's and
i haven't heard anyone else make this
point but it's kind of um
i think it's it's kind of bright which
is
if you can go and you can listen to
a louis armstrong record from 1927
and you try to approximate 1927 years
and then you can figure out what's
really special about that record
right because because the other way you
do it
like the the kind of historicist way of
do it doing it is the um
is the default right so you put on a
louis armstrong record and it's 20 20
and you listen to it and you say this
sounds like oh this sounds utterly
foreign
it's totally incomprehensible you know
there isn't a beat there you know we're
looking for all these things that are
that are present in modern music that
we're not present in
in you know in 1927 with uh with with
armstrong
and that gets in the way of us
understanding
uh what makes some of these things
special
so immediately that kind of idea uh
resonated with me and and that idea has
all kinds of implications throughout
um you know not only throughout uh uh of
you know political philosophy but also
you know our our everyday lives
so um so i decided that i was gonna work
in national security in dc
and and you know people thought i was
crazy because my my resume up at that
point was like
you know did some work uh at the
national security archive and
my degree in blah blah and then you know
i i you know skipped 10 years to go play
music
but nevertheless i managed to get myself
into that position and i got a job at
center for security policy where
where um where uh one of your guests
your future guest kyle schuyler is uh
is uh is is still working today
and um and then i just happened to meet
andrew breitbart
through that association and i met
and michael waller and a few other
people who ended up being kind of mentor
figures to me
and really gave me um a good
um a good idea
of what i wanted to do sort of in the
next
phase of my life which is to work in
political communications and information
operations
information operations man we are going
to definitely get to that that's what's
happening
all around everywhere we're
participating in that ourselves
uh one one side note on the the strauss
stuff
i i have been talking to more and more
straussians it seems these days and my
appreciation
for the old uh ism
is increasing and my sense that uh
anything new is better is also decline
diminishing
uh and uh it's interesting to to even
consider the fact that at one point
people didn't consult ancient texts and
didn't want to look backwards and didn't
see value in aristotle or plato and like
pushed it aside it was old news man old
news right
and there seems to have been and there
is a revival
among that and i guess maybe the circles
i run in are so steeped in this that
when i began to learn what straussian
really meant
i was like wait what people didn't
actually you know read the old text and
like
connect to universal truths that span
time and space in the past that's so
weird like it seems like common sense to
me
but uh it is it is sort of uh is it
fringe i don't know it's sort of like
at least it's not mainstream uh and uh
it's certainly deep in my appreciation
you know humans are humans
we've been very human-y for a long time
and people have
figured out sort of the downsides and
the upsides and how to manage things
and just because it's old doesn't mean
it's bad and i think that's something
i think that's a theme that is bubbling
up within right now
and and and should continue to carry
some some additional momentum moving
forward
yeah i think that's right and and it
really applies to anything because if
you think
you know if um
i mean what do you appreciate about if
you start to think
what you get from things that are old or
if you start to think
what do what do you get from from
anything um
it it causes you to to evaluate things i
mean it's
it it doesn't take very much to uh
you know to to kind of snap out of um of
let's say i mean we're going to talk
about modern music to just snap out of
modern music and say you know what this
this is you know this is is um
this doesn't give me anything in my soul
i'm only hearing it now because it's
being
pushed to me yeah so the minute you
start to
the minute you start to say what is this
thing that i actually like
um what is this that that i that i value
and
why do i like these things value these
things then
that you know then i think you've
already opened yourself up to
uh you know to studying to studying or
appreciating the old
well you put yourself on a rare air
just by even saying why do i think this
right right
right questioning your motives your your
own interests questioning why other
people are doing things
asking yourself that's always the
question right that's that was that was
always the question
and and and and that's always the
question that that i'm trying to uh
that i was trying to get at um i
remember
um yeah i mean ten
about you know ten years ago at least
i'm trying to figure out
you know how we got into this
predicament and i'm thinking and i'm
thinking i'm thinking i'm trying to
come up with the why that really does
answer
this question and when i said this
predicament i mean
i was thinking the question that i was
addressing at the time was
how is it that we allow
you know how is it that we allow let's
say islamists
to run around the country very freely
talking about
um you know talking about let's
you know replace it in constitutional
system with uh with islamic law
uh which which was a thing that was that
was happening
and nobody seemed to care nobody seemed
to be very very upset about it
how could this how could this be and it
occurred to me that at some point over
the last
you know 50 70 years we lost the concept
of
um of what it means you know what what's
the addition is
you know what is it what does it mean to
be um you know to be
uh in favor of the you know overthrow of
the american constitutional system
um that's you know unfortunately that's
the thing and because we didn't address
that 50
60 years ago or at any point we're in
this position now where we're just like
hey you know antifa you know it's a
lifestyle choice
you know packing the packing the supreme
court yeah you know i mean you know
everybody does
and um we're we're at this point now
where
i think we we're we're just completely
untethered not only
from the uh america of our founding but
we're completely untethered from
america of 2008 like that seems like a
lost
a lost civilization you know to us right
i was thinking a lot about that today i
saw on on on on twitter
there was an article about uh you know
nbc news said
that you know dhs is is telling it's um
it spokes people to spin for kyle
rittenhouse well okay how did it do that
dhs said hey give this guy a fair trial
so now a fair trial and equal justice
is equal to um is equal to to spinning
in favor of the guy because i guess
the the you know the moral the story is
this guy
uniquely is not allowed to have you know
he's a deplorable
he is not allowed to have equal justice
he's not allowed to be presumed innocent
until proven guilty and i mean i grew up
arguing with national lawyers guild
people and stuff like this
this is something that nobody would have
said in prior days
well we saw that uh first certainly with
kavanaugh
right like holy crap i mean there was
absolutely no presumption
of innocence and they just latched on
but you know
it's all power man there's no there's no
moral
underpinning there's no foundation
there's no rock it's just what can i do
to get power right now
what's in the air what's the mood and
these people just pounced on it and it
was disgusting to me
it was so troubling and i
i don't see that trend changing any
really like i think that this this is
getting worse yeah
yeah no i mean abs absolutely because
i mean when you're at the point where
they're openly discussing these things i
say every day there's a new
outrage every day there's a new
situation where
um where you know you think to yourself
man i did never thought it would get
like that
but you know the answer is yeah you
gotta have you know you've gotta have
uh you know more imagination i mean it's
gonna get so much worse
yeah um you know just pace yourself
right
right oh man well before we start
talking
just pace yourself goodness before you
start talking about how it's gonna get
worse
let's talk a little bit about how it's
getting better so
what is what is going on what is going
on in the middle east man
this is one of the things that i really
want to talk to you about sure
there there seems to be history
in the making in the middle east am i
overstating this am i
i'm not a mid-east expert by any means
but when i see these you know states
recognizing israel and trying to come to
peace with them
that seems to blow my mind as this has
never seen you know happened
to me i've never noticed it before like
what's going on like where where's this
coming from what's happening
explain it to us sure so
in a way where do you begin i know it's
it's hard it's hard
so so where do you begin on this stuff
and i think
that in many ways it's similar to what
we have
in the united states and in the west
when it comes to the
kind of resurgence of of of nationalism
and
maybe resurgence is the bad word because
it really is a kind of new kind of
nationalism
okay um and i think there is a
tremendous
um i think there's there's a tremendous
undercurrent of
uh of opposition
to the kind of the globalist
european uh
decadent state
that uh you know that is embodied by you
know the eu
or by um you know
50 childless uh danish
you know defense minister you know types
um who i mean you know i mean we all
know what that kind of
um we all know what kind of that that
you know
uh kind of euro deca globalist thing
um uh entails and and and a lot of
people don't want it you know they don't
want it in the west they don't want it
in the east
so at the same time as you have you have
a kind of revolution against that
going on um you realize that
in the in the middle east
let's say for the last uh couple hundred
years but really for the last
century is you've had a lot of different
fads
going on in terms of how you know how to
how to arrange
you know how to arrange government how
to arrange society in different
countries
and you go through different periods so
like you went through a um
a pan-arab phase where you know the arab
identity was paramount and we're trying
to get rid of
you know uh countries led by by egypt
and nasser we're
we're trying to to unite themselves
based on this one common identity
um you had the the folks in the middle
east
looking around during the cold war um
and looking around during world war ii
and world war one
and looking to europe and saying hey
these are successful civilizations
which ones do we want to emulate well a
lot of them wanted to emulate
the the communists and a lot of them
wanted to emulate the fascists
because they saw within islam um
you know a way to harmonize their
religion with
the modern political state so that's
when you had
you know you had situations like egypt
or nasa
had situations like you know bath party
under saddam hussein in
in iraq and um
and you know people were you know the
development of pakistan
and things like that and you know people
were kind of groping around trying to
figure out
what the next thing would be that would
sort of
um solve their problems and push them
from
you know third world into first world
because they realized after the first
world war especially that they were
woefully behind
the west so they wanted to catch up and
they wanted to use
um you know different different
political systems and political
arrangements in order to catch up
so they went through the an arab phase
they went through the the um
let's say the the the communist
socialist
um uh fascist totalitarian phase
um and then they went through an
islamist phase
and the islamist phase now is is is this
kind of the high point of that was it
was the arab spring
um but it had gone it had gone on for
you know for
30 years and that was
um exemplified both by the muslim
brotherhood and by
osama bin laden and al-qaeda and they
said hey we're going to
address this population here as the
islamic umma and
and national borders don't matter as
much because we're you know we're going
to
you know we're going to organize all
muslims to you know defend against or
defeat the crusaders the non-muslims all
around
and this was kind of the template that
we saw
before 9 11 this was the template that
people like sam huntington would see
in the in the uh in the early 90s and
late 80s
um and sort of this
this concept um after the uh the arab
spring just
just ran out of steam and it had some
help
in that respect because of the obama
administration the obama administration
totally bought into this line and and
you know
kind of unthinkingly helped along this
um this islamist phase by in fact you
know obama
gets uh you know he takes the presidency
first speech he gives he goes to cairo
and he addresses the islamic oma well
what he should have done
was he should have addressed the people
of these different countries
directly as citizens of these other
countries
um
so that's a good good point
what what was obama's motivations and we
can talk
more about what he actually did in the
middle east but like
some people people will say that he you
know was trying to undermine america and
support muslims and la
la all kinds of theories and such but
like you say unwittingly so you think
that
obama simply was mistaken in what he did
rather than
malicious um i think that's too big of a
i think that's too big of a category in
this respect i think he was mistaken
in other ways he was malicious i this
this is one of my big pet peeves about
about politics today i think
because a lot of people who come to
the right conclusion about things
tend to assume that there's no room for
people being
well-intentioned but utterly wrong yeah
and i think that encompasses most uh
that encompasses most people i mean i'm
not saying they're great people and
they're wonderful humans they're just
mistaken
i'm just saying that they could be
[ __ ] but
they have a completely different
understanding of the facts and a
completely
you know a completely ideologically
based
uh point of view that's not necessarily
consistent and that's why
they do things that they do i mean a
great example
you know for example is is uh you know
uh no conservatives
people make all kinds of ridiculous um
uh you know put neoconservatives in into
these ridiculous conspiracy
uh uh theories uh
you know i mean some of which may be
right
but to you know but it's not like they
have a
grand plan and it's not like they follow
their grand plan
completely perfectly always you know
it's a
it's um you know it it's a grand plan
that is based on ideology mistaken ideas
about human nature
um and and it's inconsistent you know
it's inconsistent between
um between what it wants on the on the
foreign policy side and what it wants
for the uh the domestic policy side
so it's not like you know i mean
we're not we're not always dealing with
um with
you know 10 foot tall super geniuses who
are who are
you know are our adversaries um there is
yeah there's a lot there's a lot of room
for being for for people being total
fuck-ups
um but yeah yeah uh
but uh but yeah so so going back to
going back to the uh
to the to the arab world yeah and it's
at a certain time after
the arab spring the arab spring was
really another word for the muslim
brotherhood coming to power and toppling
the uh
the the um uh
the the kingdoms in uh in the middle
east
sort of one after the other the and and
many of which
were actually pro-american i think syria
was the only one that was not
uh you know pro-america at that point
um i think a lot of people realized hey
wait a minute this is a dead end
and a very very strong
and assertive saudi emirati
and uh you know to lefter extent
egyptian identity
popped up and it was
let's say it was relatively secular
uh at least by the standards of you know
past
uh you know the the past limits movement
and
these people you know predominantly
under
40. these people want better lives for
themselves
um it's it's um you know they they want
at the end of the day they want um you
know less islamic law
and uh and they like their countries and
they're proud of their leaders
and um in that way they there is a
natural affinity between
places like the uae and israel and the
united states and saudi arabia and and
you know and and on and on so
in addition to the common thread of iran
we also see this
this this nationalist uh movement
happening and i think it's very positive
i think that um that at the end of the
day you know you can't make an agreement
uh you know the united states can't make
a a
peace treaty or a deal with muslim world
it's too big right it's too big any way
that you you know you can't make it with
you know the the christian world the
jewish world the
you know the zoroastrian world it's
absurd you can only make
real agreements between countries and
this is what
has has happened and um the other big
the other big issue was the uh was the
conflict between
qatar the saudi and uae that happened in
the summer of 2017.
there was a blockade and all this and
what was the what was the point
of this conflict the point of the
conflict was
saudis and emiratis and egyptians and
others were accusing the qataris
of using the muslim brotherhood and
al-jazeera
in order to destabilize their countries
which was exactly what happened during
the arab spring you know or
attempted and they said cut it out
you know we don't want your your garbage
brought
you know your your anti-regime
propaganda broadcast into our uh into
our countries
so that was sort of the genesis of this
conflict and that necessarily pushed
together
um you know it uh it sort of solidified
an anti-islamist bloc
in the middle east uh led by saudi and
uh and
the uae and and for that reason they
found a lot of commonality with
um with with the israelis because at the
same time they were coming to these
conclusions they were realizing wait a
minute
if israel disappears tomorrow and is
replaced by a palestinian terror state
led by hamas which is really the only
you know scenario that's that's been
remotely likely
um you know such as it is are we going
to be in a better position or are we
going to be in a worse position
hamas going to uh you know
is is a palestinian state going to be
um beneficial us in terms of our
security and helping us defend ourselves
against iran
is a palestinian state going to going to
be beneficial to us in terms of um
in terms of technology and in terms of
money
and scientific expertise and all these
things
so they realized wait a minute we'd
actually have a lot to um
we'd suffer a lot if israel was was gone
which was a realization that uh that
just dawned on them
after you know after after decades of
trying to remove it from the map so they
realized
wait a minute we you know we we've got a
good thing here so so that kind of
opened the door to
to uh to more settlements cooperation
and peace
okay my mind is is all over the place
there's so
so much going on in what you just said
there all right some of this is new
information to me and i'm imagining it's
new information to a lot of people
listening
so you're saying is stop me if i'm wrong
i'm trying to
give this back here a little bit yeah
trying to reflect so i can see what i
understand
that there was prior to the arab spring
there was a movement to
sort of disregard national boundaries
nation states and sort of a greater you
know people participating in a greater
thing
whether it was you know top-down imposed
european you know colonialism for
lack of a better word or the islamic
state or whatever
and so there was the arab spring was the
was the sort of sort of new version
of this new nationalism is what you're
saying where people begin to
want to define clearly their borders
their boundaries and become innate
like really solidify themselves as a
nation state
yes and that well also it was it was the
aftermath of the arab spring so
so people saw the arab spring yeah
people saw the arab spring and they said
no
no we don't want this right they don't
want it okay so
so the the impulse then to
uh self-preservation basically uh yeah
and it came to them after witnessing the
toppling of these regimes through the
arab spring
and of course the arab spring was
something and correct me if i'm wrong or
you tell me
we supported by obama administration
something that we all thought you know
american foreign policy was like yeah
let's do it right arab spring good thing
right right that it was very much
supported by the obama administration
i mean frankly it was supported by the
the obamas and also the neocons
i mean i was in jerusalem when when uh
when mubarak fell
in egypt and we were looking at that
and we watched bill crystal on tv
cheering for the overthrow of this uh
you know this
of this pro-american um uh leader
and why was he cheering he was cheering
because he said look
you know this just proves the freedom
agenda is is you know the bush freedom
agenda was real
and we said well you know it it does no
such thing because it's just going to
empower the muslim brotherhood which
ended up happening
um and and it ended up destabilizing um
you know identity stabilizing the whole
region
uh the obama the obama people were were
all in on this
and and the libya wore a great example
of how of how this worked because
you had what what that was was
a bunch of people in the obama
administration led by hillary clinton
watching al jazeera and al jazeera
qatar's al jazeera
was wall-to-wall coverage about how this
needs you know
gaddafi is is gearing up to murder all
his people
we need to intervene the west needs to
intervene america needs to intervene and
put a stop to this
well the obamas and clinton watched that
on tv
on al jazeera which which you know
clinton praised
the time for being real news and they
said oh well
we want to get in front of what the arab
street wants you know i mean if they
really want us to intervene we'll get a
lot of brownie points
from helping to topple this brutal
dictator that everyone hates
so instead of acting in america's own
interest
it tried to you know tried to kiss the
ass of the arab street as
presented by al jazeera so
it ended up toppling this uh this this
government which was
yeah i mean as as i guess as stable as
any libyan government
um can be uh
you know historically and uh and they
did it only because they wanted to
sort of get ahead of where the where
they believed the arab street was
they wanted to win they wanted to win
brownie points with um
with you know with with a bunch of
brotherhood types
which is why they did i've seen so many
conflicts between
ideas of nation state our own
nationalism the bush sort of freedom
doctrine that you said because i
remember very vividly when the war drums
were being
pounded for the iraq invasion post 9 11
it was all about
you know let's impose this our will
on these people and bring them freedom
and democracy and they're going to be so
happy and freedom and democracy is going
to spread all throughout the region
but really what it did was it kind of
destabilized
uh the secular governments and it
destabilized iraq and the whole region
and it led to
uh you know isis and the greater
transnational
pan national uh sort of movement that
we're talking about
resisting at this point and i do very
clearly remember
in the 2016 election how syria became a
real issue
and it was you know trump being like no
let's we're not going to have a no-fly
zone we're not going to go to war with
syria or with russia
and and it made him the media made him
out to be
you know pro-communist pro-terror pro
authoritarian um when in reality you
know respecting the nation's state
borders and
secular religious secular governments
and we're in sort of our long-term
interests and in israel's long-term
interest terms of respecting the
nation-state just like
as a fact right um so
bring us up a little bit further in the
story here because
i'm fascinated by this idea of the new
nationalism rising
um i'm reminded of the conversation i
had with one of my friends who
who said that uh what was it wilson who
said we need to make the world safe for
democracy
uh but now we need to make the world
safe for nationalism
and i think that this is an interesting
and fascinating subject and it also
dovetails with
conversations i've had with guys like
joe norman on complex systems
and and social distancing and globalism
in general whereas
instead of just expanding and
obliterating our boundaries
indiscriminately connecting breaking
down all the barriers
we need to actually be erect erecting
barriers
barriers of our choosing and allowing
what comes in and what comes out
social media is the same way trade is
the same way pandemic related viruses
are the same way
and so when you say that there's a new
nationalism rising in the middle east
and that it's a good thing and it's a
good thing for israel and a good thing
for america and a good thing for the the
young people
of of these countries you know that has
me you've got my attention with that
because it's all on the theme it's all
on the meta themes that we're seeing
uh around the world in all areas of our
lives right now so
let's keep moving with the story because
it is crazy it's fascinating
yeah i mean i it's it's something that
is very much
under reported and and uh you know
there's there's no analysis on this from
uh
from kind of uh let's say mainstream
sources because they want to downplay
this just as they see that
you know they see that you know populism
nationalism is the enemy
in place like europe or in brazil
um or you know in the west more broadly
uh
they they they do the same thing against
against arab
arab nationalism you know against i mean
there is no country
that has had a um a
a pr campaign against them as nasty as
saudi arabia's
has been in the last few years and i
mean saudi is a great example
because after 9 11
and we we made demands on saudi arabia
and we said hey you know you have to do
you know these
you know the you you have to fight the
jihadists in in these ways and
and you know we want you to you know to
change your textbooks we want you to do
all these things
to uh to let's say prevent uh islamic
radicalism and
radicalization and and and then the
growth of jihadism
well okay so they did that you know
today they they um you know they saudi
arabia
used to be um uh used to be a hub of the
muslim brotherhood
you know for example the muslim world
league is is a great example it was like
a
a um it was a an ngo
started by the brotherhood with saudi
money out of riyadh
and it was created to
you know it was created as a forum and
a way to educate um
young muslims all around the world in
muslim brotherhood doctrine i mean i
know i i collect
these old books i have a series of
brotherhood
uh uh books put out by muslim world
league you know that they it was run
by huma abedin's dad who was you know
brother hit you know long long
brotherhood lineage
and you know saudis realized we're not
going to pay for this anymore
so they went and they got rid of the the
whole brotherhood influence from the
modern world
and they replaced it with a guy alisa
who
made it his mission to be um you know to
be sort of the the uh interfaith you
know peace conciliatory guy
between uh between muslims and jews and
christians
and he's been great on this he's been
great on this
um he he wrote an open letter uh
to to um to muslim
candidates for office in the united
states saying it's your responsibility
not to follow islamic law it's your
responsibility to follow american law
and the constitution so like this is all
good stuff that that like frankly they
should be getting so much credit for
that
many of us who have been talking about
um
who've been talking about uh you know
the jihadist space have been demanding
finally we're getting it and and
you know as far as the media is
concerned now that's the problem
so it you know you'll see uh
uh the crown prince mbs being referred
to as an authoritarian
and this and that i mean it's it's you
know
uh as far as the media goes they're big
enemies you know trump
uh orban in in hungary mbs
bolsonaro bb netanyahu
all of these guys have a common um
you know have have have have common
connections
and at the end of the day they're all
strong nationalists
and they're against um you know they're
against the eu they're against
uh let's say what we think of as the
you know intra national global super
state they're
they are for sovereignty for their
people
and their country i think that's what it
comes down to at the end of the day
is that a lot of this is a sovereignty
issue
and um uh a lot of this is a sovereignty
issue and people understand that
you know a country with without borders
or or a world without borders is is a
tyranny it's necessarily a tyranny
uh because the borders allow for
different experiments i mean you know
it's federalism writ large the borders
allow for different experiments based on
different
uh values customs heritage
and once you get rid of the borders you
have to say well
you know we all have to agree on a
particular system we all have to agree
on our
particular values or beliefs and and
that's that and if you don't i guess you
get punched
but um so so you know i mean
what you say is completely right we we
are witnessing a return to those borders
and
return to uh to kind of embrace
the the things that make america america
and hungary hungary
and you know israel israel etc and on
and on
and uh and um
uh you know i mean in the middle east
right now is a great example of that and
i think as we
progress over the next couple of years i
think we'll
we'll you know if we if we
if our country hasn't come apart and we
have the luxury
of looking abroad and um
and uh uh you know with a critical eye
of seeing what's going on over there i
think we'll we'll
we'll see that things are heading in in
a much better direction now that's
totally
um you know to hear someone say that
about
the middle east is kind of wacky and
wild but um
that's where we are
fascinating how the bush freedom wars
the neocon wars which were meant to
bring democracy and freedom to everybody
and improve american relations and power
and all that and
get the oil and blah blah has second and
third order consequence of actually
developing
a nationalism that the united states can
look to
as something that's valuable and
worthwhile
uh how do you think
where did trump get his foreign policy
ideas
how and what did he do and why did he go
to saudi arabia like
first thing put the hands on the globe
the sparkling globe thing uh which
looked to me something out of spencer so
i don't know
so it's really weird yeah yeah yeah um
how where did where did his policy trust
come from whose ideas are they who's
pushing for this stuff in the
administration
why did he go to saudi arabia first did
he have a master plan
is this four years in the making like
let's talk
go yeah yeah so i can answer some of
those questions
so yes it is four years in the making
um yes they did have an idea exactly
when they walked in
in the door of you know a vague idea of
what they wanted to accomplish now of
course it looks
a lot more uh real and tangible in
retrospect
but at the time i can tell you what they
were thinking because i was
you know i was i was there and talking
to them
um they understood very smartly
that the obama administration had for
eight years
tried to de-prioritize our relationships
with um with israel and also with the um
uh with the gulf arab you know chiefly
saudi arabia and
um it had done the obama folks had done
that
by elevating iran by making a deal with
uh
with iran and uh and and look really
looking the other way while it wreaked
havoc throughout the region
and uh with you know their fear militias
and death squads
and uh and and terrorism and things like
that i mean
when the uh trump administration
first walked through the door the
iranians were kind of de facto in
control of five
capitals in the uh in the region uh you
know
you had beirut with with hezbollah you
had um
you had uh sana and yemen you had
um baghdad in iraq
uh you had um damascus and syria
and uh and then you also had um
and then of course you also had iran so
these companies these countries were
were you know slowly being taken over
by iran and this had to stop the obama
people were
you know totally behind this at least it
showed no indication that they
they put up any resistance and i think
the trump people came in saying yeah we
got to reverse this and bring it back to
sort of the natural state of affairs
um and and that's what they said about
doing you know there's a reason why the
first trip was to saudi arabia because
saudi arabia is the
most uh important uh country in the
region
that is uh that is muslim and
very significantly he went to saudi
arabia and then he also went to
jerusalem
at the same time same trip and i think
people saw this
um and and finally our our allies there
who had you know lost their voice
already screaming for for eight years um
uh uh against the um
against the obama administration they
were very happy to see that
you know somebody is you know that uh
they have an ally back in the white
house so
this is so this is what's going on i
think in general too as far as israel
goes
it just it just shows that um
for the last several decades the the
assumption was
that in order to get a good deal in the
middle east
the the american administration whoever
it is
is going to have to put the screws to
israel and make it accept
you know make it accept uh
you know a whole bunch of things the
international community wants it to
accept
well the answer is that's not how you do
it the answer is what you do is you
you make the uh you make the the rest of
the world
let's say in this case the rest of the
arab world understand that you know
guess what you're not going to
diplomatically destroy israel
the same way that you wanted to
militarily destroy it
once that's off the table and once you
say hey this is a permanent thing that's
not that you know you're not going to be
able to make this disappear
then you can actually talk and then you
can um
and then you can uh you can solve
problems i mean it's the same way
it's like when uh on one side when one
side wants to
to to uh make an agreement and the other
side says well
the you know the the end of my agreement
is gonna be
that you die why have the negotiation
why bother why you know but once you
accept that like yes you're both going
to leave here
you know alive okay now we can you know
now we can talk now we can we
you know we can we can figure this out
um so so that was
that was another big thing that uh the
trump people knew going in
that uh that they were that they were
going to do i mean i'm not saying that
things didn't fall in the lap and i'm
not saying that um
that they did all of this you know
tremendous amount of credit
um to to the leaders of these countries
because at the end of the day they're
the ones that uh
that uh you know that kind of grabbed
the ring and and uh
and made this possible so there is a
coherence
right i think that there there is
obviously a sense
a media line excuse me that that the
trump
trump is incoherent babbling has no
logic
has no sense he's just a bull and he's
just breaking
breaking plates and destroying the china
shop and pooping all over the town
and he does it all impulsively without
any thinking but there is a coherence
between talking about american
nationalism on showing onshoring
american manufacturing doing deals that
favor the american people versus the
uniparty and the corporate state
and trans transnational corporations
there is a coherence between that
and the foreign policy approach taken in
the middle east
and i i pray i hope
history looks back on that and sees a
coherence
and that gets for me like becomes more
obvious and crystallized
after the noise goes away right like so
much all this [ __ ] is noise the daily
social media the daily media uh
misdirections the the fast
transient things that they shoot into
the info space to distract everybody and
get us all confused and worked up
once that stuff calms uh and and they
start to look back and judge the trump
administration
as a four-year unit or an eight-year
unit and then contextually within
history
uh i think that there's gonna be a
greater appreciation for what has taken
place
uh i don't think anybody maybe you did
but like mainstream wise nobody said
oh trump's gonna come into office and
peace in the middle east
it's gonna break out um but uh i did
i did i did uh i mean i didn't know this
in 2016
but uh by 2017 i i had an idea of what
was
what was coming um and i was saying it i
was tweeting it
nobody gave me the time of day i was
going on mainstream
you know shows and people would laugh at
me and uh
and at the end i mean i don't give a
[ __ ] i i i knew that i knew that i was
right and and
it's another example of how
um how let's say mainstream media not
not only media but kind of mainstream um
uh political analysis for our policy
analysis of
this it's just garbage it's absolute
garbage it's all group think
it's all i it's it's you know things
starting from an ideological premise and
working them working their way backwards
to fill in the facts
um you know a lot of us were
pointing this out i mean i know people
in the white house were there who used
to be there
um uh sort of had this on their mind
because
you can't i mean take a look at twitter
open up twitter take a look at
you know saudi twitter and emirati
twitter and things like this
and you'll see people who you know
normal people who have more in common
with us as you know folks on the right
um than uh you know than a lot of our
fellow americans have with us
and and that's not just the middle east
you know
it's it's also the case throughout um
you know throughout the world where you
see a lot of these populist movements uh
bringing up um and
and i think that's a really special uh
situation that we're in and um
it doesn't pretend well for social
cohesion in the united states
uh because it kind of shows the divide
that the divide between
us as americans is uh is
is far greater than you know many old
divides
used to be between uh between enemy
states
indeed indeed uh i keep returning to the
idea that there is
in in american foreign policy
or i don't know you know it's so
inconsistent all over the place so i
can't make any generalizations but
there's these two notions right
of like acceptance and plurality
and and sort of like your dominating
hegemonic sort of
viewpoint or thrust where you want to go
and i feel like uh
domestically there are people who uh
will will scream for pluralism plurality
in in america but then abroad
you know want a hedge a hegemonic
perspective and like it's
you know america only right and there's
a conflict between what happens
with us domestically and what's
happening around the world
and you and i were talking earlier and
you noted
that as the middle east appears to be
coming together
and in a way accepting their plurality
we're
tearing ourselves apart at home
because some people can't actually
accept a plurality
uh and it's just an interesting
dichotomy what are you feeling right now
like
do you feel things coming together there
and things coming apart
here why is that happening what is the
balance
are they related yeah i mean
i think they're related in the sense
that um you know what
kind of the phenomenon that we're just
talking about about um
if you want to say you know nationalism
be globalism
on on a world state kind of country to
country uh in that respect but
you know we're coming apart really it
was it was bloom
that convinced me i mean i i had an idea
then that we were coming apart in an
irreconcilable way
um you know when after after reading uh
bloom
because at the end of the day we don't
have an agreement on what justice is
[Music]
between us and these are really the most
important things
and and you know he he kind of made me
see that that
the things that we describe as
you know the the things that that i mean
if we don't have concepts of that
in common if we have no understanding
for example equal justice
right of equal justice under the law
or or you know let's say a guy a man
is uh you know a man is
uh is not guilty or innocent based on
his race
but based on the things that he has done
that seems so
basic it seems so basic
um and yet we have half our population
has given up that that concept
completely
so what do you do about that how do you
how do you
teach how do you teach people
that concept because that is a fragile
enlightenment thing
and that's not that that is thing that
took you know tens of thousands of years
to develop
initially and to lose it is very very
easy and i mean we've seen we've
we've lost it let's say in the last 30
years uh but really intensely
only in the last you know five or ten
but it could take
another 300 years to bring it back for
people to really understand the
consequences of these things
i mean when i was growing up and we're
probably around
you know the same age we used to
we used to talk about the skokie nazis
and that was an issue i mean i went to a
religious jewish school
and one of the debates that we had in in
class was
okay do you outlaw you know the the
nazis marching in
um in in skokie illinois where they have
a large
um uh population of holocaust survivors
and jews
and you know and we sort of debate this
thing
in you know fourth grade or fifth grade
and
and the teacher made us see that you
know you can't
you know i mean you know you you can't
ban them
because there are larger principles at
stake they're a larger kind of freedom
principles at stake and
at the end of the day in order to agree
to live in
a country that has freedom you're going
to have to accept the messy result
which is that you know a bunch of
holocaust survivors
have to see some nazis marching down the
street okay well
you you accept that result for
the more important result of being able
to express yourself freely
and have free association um you know
across the board
so it's like you know the the you know
you accept the bad thing in order to
make the much
the much better more important thing
possible well
we've lost sight of that i mean even you
know
the aclu which which which fought you
know on behalf of the nazis
today would do no such thing
you know because because they'll they'll
claim that um
you know they'll claim that uh that you
know the presence of the nazis
constitutes
you know physical harm and emotional
yadda yadda
so yeah so once once we've abandoned
that i mean what what what do we have
left
there there is definitely a competing
notions of justice
uh in our society today a lot outlined
very well i think it's caldwell
outlined that in age of enlightenment uh
but
certainly we have an idea of justice of
equal opportunity
and then there's a competing invalid
uh notion of uh equal outcomes and
therefore
instead of our version justice uh sort
of
liberating freedoms and allowing
freedoms
and the the competing notion is actually
takings from people
and givings to others in what is
necessarily an arbitrary and capricious
manner
and so these completing notions of
justice
are are so fundamentally problematic
because
america whatever you want i mean i
talked to anton about american
nationalism what does it mean where does
it come from it's definitely
something to debate uh but uh the the
if if we don't at least have an
agreement on justice
then we really don't have an agreement
on
anything and i have a personal
experience with the aclu i can tell you
dude when i got boxed when i got doxxed
in 2018 by antifa i had written some
things critical of feminism critical of
immigration uh sanctuaries and they
they thought i was a nazi antifa and so
they doxed me to my employer said i was
a nazi got me fired
the the director the legal director of
the aclu in washington dc art spitzer
he reached out to me and he said hey man
this is clear violation of your first
amendment rights you work for a
quasi-governmental agency you're
protected first amendment plus
other protections in dc he spent weeks
working with me
he wrote like a big paper he helped me
with research
and then he presented it to his judicial
committee
to take the case officially and they
rejected it
and he was very disappointed he said he
was the last remaining member of the
libertarian wing of the aclu
and then he appealed it to the larger
committee board at large
and they denied it as well on the
grounds
quote they didn't want to offend their
coalition partners
their coalition partners being human
rights campaign
and black lives matter among others and
the aclu has spun out of control in such
a way that it's now
like a farce i was raised to believe
that the aclu
was american it was the statue of
liberty
it was here to protect us they were
going to protect the constitution and
your freedoms and your liberty and if
the aclu was involved it was an
important real matter that needed to be
addressed and it was likely very adjust
cause
and now it's a farce just like every
other institution in america
just like the american psychological
association saying that being a boy is
toxic and bad and evil
just like uh you know my kids schools
being
my kids being forced to sit through
struggle sessions that have to examine
their whiteness
and disregard whatever negative feelings
they're having
about thinking this is wrong you know so
the the collapse of the american
institution
is is something that is very troubling
to me it's continuing to
accelerate and these competing notions
of justice are kind of at its core
how do we resolve that dave
all right so i that was my question i
was going to cut you off and say all
right so what do you do about it
yeah um asking you you're the guest
expert sir
i look i have to tell you i don't think
there's anything you can do
i don't think there's anything you can
do i think we're on a natural
um i think we're on a we're on a a kind
of
natural glide path to um maybe decline
is not the
right word but yeah i mean it's it's
it's a breakdown
of um our understanding of
you know it's a kind of the foundations
of the regime i mean that's where we're
that's where
basically where we're at um i have been
i've gotten a lot of crap
because over the last several years
um in public i mean i've had this
position in private for for longer
but i've been in favor of a national
divorce
um i think at the end of the day there's
only one way out of this
and which is to um for
for those of us who believe in um
you know let's say the old america arca
has founded
um even america up until you know the
the
the late 90s early 2000s uh we're going
to have to retreat
to defensible geographic boundaries
defensible meaning
um in a a a geographic region where
the polity is you know relatively um
conservative where we can actually vote
and get
the things that we want um i think
people will
of course a lot of objections to this
and they'll say okay the you know the
new america will be much poorer um
and less secure etc etc but i think at
the end of the day
um and as as we go forward more people
will realize that
um they would trade this new scenario in
you know in a heartbeat for what they
have now which is you know which is
basically a woke tyranny
and it's not getting any better um
there's not a magic button this is what
kind of frustrates me about many of the
uh
you know many of my friends in kind of
the
the uh the old reaganite um
mold who just say well you know we can
meet this we just need a couple more
elections we need to do this
[ __ ] you know not to be too dark
about this
but you don't have the people
you know you i mean meaning we we don't
have the people to go and to staff
we couldn't stop the 4 500 jobs in the
trump administration
in the executive branch we could not
staff them with people who didn't hate
donald trump you know we couldn't fill
those jobs
um how are we going how are we going to
to replace everyone you know in the
administrative state that
uh that that can sabotage it what
happens when i mean it's great you had
you know roofo on the show he's doing
amazing work you know one of my heroes
um you know managed to succeed in
getting the trump administration to uh
to push back on critical race theory and
and um and all these things totally
wonderful and that's great
what happens when trump leaves office
what happens when
and next you know i mean we're not gonna
have uh
we're not going to have a trumpian
government forever
what happens when um when the left
takes takes power again wins an election
and and and and puts their pedal to the
metal with this stuff
you know it's we're never
uh we're never winning the battle
completely
uh the the most that we can do in in in
this case is to
is is basically to you know to to tread
water and to survive a little bit
that's why i say the long-term prognosis
here is
to divide the country and uh and and and
really to to get out
and to attempt to build new institutions
that um you know from the ground up
that are maybe more modest um
and and and more geographically
contained so i
i i really don't see um a
a good future for the united states
in terms of the things that that that we
believe i just i just don't
you know i see it man i see it and
you're making me
breathe heavy over here because it's
it's sad
it's sad uh the analogy
i like to bring up is that at some point
you gotta realize
you're you're in a burlap sack with a
cobra
and you know who's gonna come out right
like remember ricky tikitavi they used
to take the mongrels and open the sack
with the cobra
tie it up and who you know who's going
to win right there's only one
one choice and uh that's where we are
and i don't think that people
realize that yet or have come to accept
it uh
that the the the whole thing that's
based in
largely critical race theory and
progressivism and the radical left
it's not radical in the sense that
they've taken over all the institutions
they're not fringe
they may be small minority but they're
exceptionally powerful
and they're in extremely high leverage
positions and they have can what's the
word that they
converge they've like converged all of
these
major institutional pillars within the
country and even the world basically
said even with four more years of trump
we're still not going to eradicate that
that's what people don't get sometimes
is that trump is not only
fighting against critical race theory
the woken those people but he's also
fighting within his own government
he's got it's not as if he came in took
over the government and all of a sudden
there was an army acting in unison and
everybody's supporting it as you pointed
out
he has to struggle on a daily basis just
to get things done
i random i i just
think about what the world would have
looked like or what the trump
administration would look like had
anton bannon beatty and
others stuck around and had a chance
to and flynn had a chance to actually
implement you know maybe in a more
robust manner
uh what the president uh had uh
had correctly identified as major issues
for us moving forward
unfortunately the the the deconstruction
of the united states and and the
erection of more barriers
uh is on theme globally um
we're seeing it all over the place we
see it in science we see it in
biology we see it in the pandemic we are
social distancing
is going to become sort of
our country's infrastructure like the
setup i mean
it's it's ironic that we're being ironic
i don't know that's right word
it's shitty and weird that we're being
introduced to this notion of social
distancing through the pandemic
but at the same time it's like okay so
maybe it isn't
entirely healthy for us to all be
together rubbing shoulders and on the
same team and maybe we just do need to
take a step back and erect a barrier
decide what comes through and what
doesn't in a healthy way just like your
cells do
inside of your body and you know
that trend is squarely in place
unfortunately and so what what do you
think people
should do on a well no
i'm not going to get to that i want to
talk a little bit more even about the
the internal forces that are working to
destabilize our current regime
and when you say regime the first time i
read it in a context i didn't read it
neutral right i read regime i'm like oh
negative that's horrible right nasty but
it just means
you know sort of our established system
of government yeah
and so uh talking to darren
he's pretty convinced that the similar
tactics that were used
in eastern europe and perhaps arab
spring and
elsewhere are being used here in the
united states in the version
of what he called color revolution do
you think that there is
a connection between what's happening in
the united states the preparation for
fighting the election the litigation
the information you know pollution of
the
information space the mass uprisings
quote peaceful protests etc is there
really a relationship between
that and and arab spring and and uh
color revolutions in europe i mean
is it the same thing is the same thing
happening are they the same people
that's making this happen
what are your thoughts on that yeah i
mean i largely agree with darren on this
point
um a lot of the criticisms that have
come his way
both from uh you know from deep state
people and also from people who are
you know who are uh more friendly have
kind of focused and fixated on the term
color revolution
which at the end of the day it doesn't
matter what you call it
right we're talking about a particular
phenomenon in the same way that
a lot of these folks went crazy when the
first time i think rush limbaugh used
the word deep state
and everyone was like no it's not like
the deep state in in turkey and in egypt
well no it's not like the deep state in
turkey in egypt
but it is a thing that you know i mean
it's it's shorthand let's not get
too hung up on the name when we're
describing a particular phenomenon
so but i think darren is right about
that um
it is a kind of remarkable um
cast of characters that that happens to
overlap between
the um specifically the eastern european
color revolution guys
and uh and and the folks who are
interested in
in removing trump i think it's a slam
dunk
case to be made that a
um a bunch of these guys see trump as
an illegitimate totalitarian um
you know pro-russia strong man figure
uh you know and and b are going to use
every instrument
at their disposal to try to dispatch him
um you know based on popular uprisings
and the claim of
uh you know and um you know based on
voting irregularities and things like
that i think to to
to not see that that is going on
is to be you know more than blind
um so so i think he's got a very good
good point there
um it's really easy yeah i mean it's
it's it's really easy to see i mean this
is
this is the the united states has had
this particular capability in its
toolkit and i think what i know that
you know my my old friend uh eli lake
was was kind of very critical of this
particular
um this particular terminology because
in his mind it kind of um
it didn't give enough credit to some of
the local
folks on the other end of uh in
some of the local folks who were kind of
democratic activists in some of these
countries i don't think darren was
necessarily when he used the word color
revolution making a point and saying
that all of these were particularly
illegitimate
i think in general he was talking about
the particular toolkit
and a map of how you do it and i know
there's a map
how you do it i mean the guy that that
he had referenced has a book on
you know this is this is how you do it
you know you mobilize
right a um a playbook exactly right
so um i think that's sort of what we
have to look forward to but
for this for this election but we're in
a weird spot
because the um
because the left found that especially
after
uh after kenosha
rioting doesn't benefit you know the
democratic party
so they're going to have to figure out
how to put a lid on their
rioting until after the election a
and and and b you know they may not even
ride after the election because it does
turn people off
you know let's say it let's say it's for
grabs and we
you know it's after the election a few
weeks later we still don't know who won
pardon of my my my background here keep
keeping it real we still don't know who
won
but you know so right now we're fighting
in in the american public
uh for for the legitimacy of of you know
one of the
of the two candidates well i don't think
it's going to benefit
the democrats to have the whole united
states convulsed
in you know anti-trump riots
after the election i don't think they're
going to benefit from that um
so they're going to have to make
adjustments to their political playbook
and their in the strategic playbook
uh considering that look i i mean on the
other hand
had it not been for this summer had it
not been
for seattle and portland and all this
stuff i think it would be looking
very different kind of strategy for the
democrats in terms of the color
revolution
i think you know i had the people not
gotten sick of rioting
there would have been you know that they
would have been
uh they would have been burning cities
down in in in november and december but
whether or not they do i think that
still remains to be seen yeah
it does remain to be seen i i get the
sense that there's a little bit of a
genie out of the bottle effect
um i know that antiques i mean they've
lost control
yeah a little bit yeah uh i think that
the the black lives matter and antifa i
know for a fact that they've been
operational and doing things for many
many years before just now
and they've been training and and
indoctrinating
and gearing up and and even they even
took a little pause if you
remember 2018 it seemed as though
some of this stuff started to chill 2019
start to chill a little bit but we kind
of knew that they were just laying in
weight
and ready to come back in 2020 and here
they are i suspect that uh
if there will be an outburst november
3rd
there will be an outburst january
whatever
when trump gets inaugurated again uh
should he win hopefully uh and so i i
think there's going to be a lot more of
that
the thing that you brought up earlier
that i see as a common thread in all of
this
is you talked about information
operations and
it's such a powerful uh and pervasive
the information battle space the
information landscape
you know what is your involvement in
information operations what does it mean
to you
what can we expect to see over the next
month two three months you know in terms
of information
operations how are people screwing with
their minds how are they
dominating narratives tell me tell me
what you think about that
well it's it's a big topic but um
and and people have been writing about
this about this forever but
the way i think about it is kind of
simple um
i think of information operation as
you know when when you're in the world
of politics you want to get a specific
you want to get to a specific policy
outcome
and you say okay how am i going to get
to this specific
policy outcome i need to get people to
believe
x in order then to do why and
since we're in politics and it's and
sort of the nature of this world
is is information these are the tools
that we use in order to get you know in
order to
to to get the point across so for
example
totally basic uh example actually this
one is from um
this one is from edward barnet um in
probably in 1920 this example is from
where he is approached by
he is approached by a magazine and the
magazine says
we want more subscribers
not only do we want more subscribers we
want more important subscribers
so this is okay so that's sort of let's
say the policy goal is more important
subscribers
so he says okay and uh he he will go
and he
puts together a an investigative piece
in the magazine um that
is you know provocative and
groundbreaking and contains all kinds of
you know interesting new information
let's think of it as like a new yorker
article today
you know big long profile expose
of you know the war in afghanistan or
something
and then once he puts it out he will
then go
and he will organize a bunch of people
to
to also write about it write about that
article
and by writing about it you're promoting
it in the same way that
you know you have a book available on
amazon and you get a bunch of your
friends to go and fill out reviews
and then you've got a bunch of positive
reviews and and you know
and and uh you you get your friends to
tweet about it which just bounces
back it's that all that is information
that just bounces back to the original
uh link so that you keep selling more
books
okay then you go and you have
uh you have the subject of this
particular article
um let's say
you know someone will go and take this
article and say okay i'm going to
make a congressional hearing out of this
particular piece of information
so i will also get the benefit of you
know x number of news cycles as we talk
about the hearing
i will put together 10 witnesses and
everybody's going to be talking about
the same thing and the same thing
and each time everyone is going to uh to
talk about the new yorker article or the
atlantic article
or i mean we just saw this with the
atlantic with the with the with the bs
story about uh about
uh suckers and losers
um i mean how much how much uh you know
how much um
you know new space i'm gonna use
you know new cycles did they get all
that they got they got several
right so then final you know then then
you have your congressional hearing
and then you uh you know let's say the
president mentions your story
and you get another little bit so what
you're doing here
to make a long story short is you are
you are
constructing a media campaign
that is based off little bits of
information
and little media events that you can
contrive and put together
in order to accomplish what you want
which is in barney's case
to sell more copies or in the case of
the atlantic
to get trump out of office to get you
know i mean that was a
perfect information if you think about
it targeted
because it was specifically targeted
towards
military voters where trump is strong
they wanted to undermine the military
voters
i think because they wanted to push a
coup
point of view and they wanted to get
they wanted to make it more likely for
um for military leaders to to get
involved
um you know in order to eject trump but
regardless
they wanted to to to attack a part of
trump's base
so that's why they did the story so
you know uh long story short that's what
an information operation
is and you have your many component
parts but basically it's just built by
um by uh
little shards and strands of information
that you
kind of put together in a in a um in a
coherent way
right and then a coordinated
reinforcement doubling down uh
persuasion
through authority by getting popular
people and authority figures and
whatever to regurgitate them
strategically leaking information
so the reason why i wanted to bring this
up is because for the
listeners i just want people to
challenge
what you're reading and hearing and ask
yourself
why am i hearing about this today
why are these people talking about this
story about trump generals or whatever
today
why are they talking about trump saying
something stupid about catholics which i
don't think he really did you know why
are we hearing these things in the news
and then when you start to ask and this
is how we started off the conversation
why
why when you start to ask why about
things
you start to see the interconnections
you start to see
the manipulation and you start to sense
a motivation coming at you rather than a
fact coming at you and if you can begin
to see the world
like that as just competing motivations
and then
uh i'm going to say 3d chess but not in
the way other people are thinking about
it
we're chess boards stacked up on top of
chess boards and people
are moving pieces here and moving pieces
here and everybody is is a
is a piece in someone else's chess game
and we're moving people's minds around
through information and through
persuasion through motivation through
media manipulation
which is why things like this talk and
why things like on twitter and podcasts
are so valuable and so important these
days so that we can
talk about these things in a way i have
no i i'm not
in the in the government and i'm not
running for office
i'm my goal here is just to get after
the truth and to just
understand you know there's just such a
uncomfortable feeling when you begin to
realize how we're being manipulated
and and it makes it feel like you're
taking a step through like fog and you
don't know where the ground is and
everything is uncertain
and it just is is an unsettling
ungrounded
feeling and and we're we're purposefully
being confused right like if you feel
confused
that's what they want right yeah yeah
and
a very important point you brought up is
is you know
why am i seeing this today yes that's
the question to ask why am i seeing this
today
we have this idea that
probably the most important thing that
that
that in any of our viewers or listeners
could if they could take away from
is is to know this the days when
you had uh journalists on a beat
you know walking down the street with
the ear to the ground
trying to find a story those days are so
those days are long
over when you see an article in in the
wall street journal
or the washington post or the new york
times or
politico or whatever that story was
pitched
by someone like me right that story was
pitched by
by someone just like me who who already
showed up with the narrative with
four or five sources and the only thing
that reporter has to do is maybe
do a little typing you know maybe pull
pull the story together
often even that doesn't happen but
that's how it works and you know if if
you
if you look at a story every day like
that
and you try to piece together i mean you
could if you
you a layman can sit down and read a
story in one of these mainstream outlets
specifically
in terms of national security can look
at one of these articles and say hey
i from this article i have a reasonable
idea
of who was behind this
if not an individual than like a type of
person
you know let's say you know state
department you know
a person leak this who is opposed to
this and that policy etc and break down
who are the you know who
uh you know even even who some of the
blind quotes are
so it's it's possible to um and i think
really important
for um american news consumers
to be able to sit into and to and to
sort of read the tea leaves and and
decipher what's going on with um
with their national security related um
uh uh news stories because it's all
it's almost all junk and it's all
put out on purpose there's no such thing
as hey we're just reporting the news
you know everything everything is fun
everything is fun and
to figure out what they're trying to do
on any given day with any given article
is part of being able to decipher what
is happening
right so what we call this in the
liminal order we call this
sense making so we call it we we call
sense making we define it as intentional
understanding or intentional knowing
so we like we concentrate it's part of
personal sovereignty right
is to develop a sense of sense making
and that's an intentional understanding
and intentional knowing
and it's not being a passive receiver of
information
it's being critical at all times asking
yourself the motivations of the person
delivering it the timing of it
and trying to really come up with a a a
strengthened muscle of sense-making
so that you can maintain a sense of
personal sovereignty
and maintain control of your own
viewpoints and of your own emotions
and to not have your passions be riled
up uh uh
undes you know unwillingly you know by
somebody else
and so uh in in today's environment
and moving forward i can't see any way
that this is going to diminish
but developing a sense of sense-making
as an essential component to personal
sovereignty
is a skill that we all need to learn and
it needs to go
it needs to go way beyond what they
teach in high schools where they're like
oh you can't use wikipedia as a source
has to go
way beyond that uh and unfortunately
it is like we said it's intentional
understanding intentional knowing
you have to also be intentional in
practicing and developing this skill
and that's something that we work on
every day in the liminal order we've got
sense making workshops and sense making
seminars
and we operate collectively as like an
info militia
and when i say info militia i mean this
in the sense that a militia arises when
the government fails to provide
necessary security and in this case it's
an information
environment and so we are a group of
people that have come together to make
sense of the world
and we are effectively an info militia
in this sense
and it's basically a nation even
worldwide intelligence network that
brings information together we digest it
and synthesize it as a team
and then we can have a a reasonably
accurate world view
and we found it to be tremendously
powerful so i'm hoping that this idea of
sense making makes it out there into the
world and that it's a
a critical life skill it's like
balancing the checkbook man you got to
be able to make sense
to sensemake and how to intentionally
understand
the world rather than being a passive
receiver of information which
is more times than not a manipulated uh
you know sort of information operation
as you said uh
as an aside a great book on this subject
is trust me i'm lying by ryan holiday
uh that is a fantastic book it's a great
easy read
he's funny and he lays it all out on how
these information things happen all the
news cycles happen
i've adopted a few of the tactics that
he outlined
in that book as well and it's it's
powerful stuff man
it's powerful i love that book i gave i
gave away
several copies of that book um when when
it first came out
and when i first read it um i
his you know his sections on andrew
breitbart
i think are unfair um you know i mean
i knew him then so i was in a position
i'm in a position to kind of refute some
of those uh
some of those those barbs but uh but
still
you're totally right about about that
book
i also think that that book is
the advice he gives is not really
possible for someone on the right
um in many ways because it takes for
granted
that you you know it takes for granted
that you're not in an adversarial
position with the rest of the media
right um and that and you have that as
you know you have uh a will media
ready to disseminate for you um so
a great book would be how to hack
you know the media for you know for for
those of us on the right
but i don't think anyone would want to
give up their secrets
right well uh say what you want about
laura loomer but she has figured that
out she's figured out how to hack the
major media systems in some ways
uh when she was silenced off of twitter
and whatnot
uh but i also think that there is some
semblance of this ecosystem that ryan
talks about
happening on the right um guys like
myself
and others sort of in my sort of
latitude we
we source stuff it gets out there in the
morning
and then by the afternoon the bigger
accounts pick it up and then by the
night time it's on tucker carlson
and i've seen this happen personally a
number of times
and uh one it just shows the tucker's
producers are following all of us and
have their ear to the ground very very
intently
uh and two it just shows that there
really is a media ecosystem where you
can surface
information and bubble stories and
narrative up i know you know
i know you know i know you know about
some of this stuff
uh you've mentioned some of the subject
matters that you've been involved in
throughout this conversation
and uh it's it's fascinating to me just
to see how it all works and how in some
in many cases this is
an emergent phenomenon it's not a
top-down directed kind of thing it's
just like
we're all in the arena and we're making
it happen and the and the right things
sort of
have a way of making themselves known
and surfacing to the top and if you can
be connected to the right nodes or
become a node yourself
then you become very powerful and we saw
that really evolve in 2016
uh with the sort of maga sphere on
twitter and information space uh
evolution then and back then you know a
lot of us were
uh neophytes and new to that game and
this time around man this is our second
is my second go around i know some other
guys our second go round we're battle
tested
battle hardened been through us know
what it looks like what it feels like
and i think to some extent that gives us
a slight advantage this time but
um you know the information space is one
that's polluted on purpose the
journalists are
are stupid on purpose they're poorly
educated they're indoctrinated the obama
administration very famously said
that the reporters are stupid and
they'll do what they have no life
experience
and they'll do they'll write anything
that we say anything
at any time and you know the fact that
everybody in america doesn't know this
it's mind-boggling
but we'll continue to push continue to
push it out
and i get frustrated i get texts from my
sister like
you know please help me my my liberal
friends just think that donald trump
did you know supports white supremacists
and she's a progressive and she's just
like trying to help
these people with their confusion
everybody's feeling confused
when you're confused you can be
manipulated and that's pretty much where
we are right now which is sad so as we
started the conversation we'll end it
with
an urge to people to ask why always ask
why
ask the motivations of what you're
observing ask
why this is happening it will make you a
happier healthier person
once you get past the existential dread
that comes from asking all those
questions
once you get past that it will make you
a happier healthier person there's no
doubt about it
right no no i mean i'm glad i'm glad you
pointed out the existential dread
because it is a thing
it's totally a thing you know the more
you the more often you do this and the
more time you spend
in the hall of mirrors here you know
which is
this this particular world that we're
talking about
um the more it can get you down and the
more it can
you know a lot of people sort of going
back to
to you know the end of america and the
place where we're at
kind of um in a in a in a meta way in
this country
you can look at that and you can say
well it's over
i'm not gonna fight anymore i'm not
gonna do this because
there's no way and you know when when i
say that the old arrangement is over
it's not an invitation to lay down and
be depressed
and and that i mean let's hope you have
a more
let's hope you've got more imagination
than that you know
that is to say that
it's time to start thinking about new
and novel arrangements
yeah and it's time to say you know if if
if the
if the old order no longer makes sense
if the old way of organizing
um you know the the united states no
longer makes sense
then maybe another you know maybe
another one will make more sense and
only if we hash out these things and in
in a way that uh that we're not afraid
to do in a way that you know we're
we're not intimidated we're not limited
by our
um you know
by you know things that we're afraid to
think
and things that we're afraid to know
only then can we can we really
um you know go go forward and figure out
how to solve some of these problems
yeah one thing that comes to mind here
as we're going to wrap this up is
it's a great great way to end too it's
you're talking about a challenging
environment an unpredictable future one
that potentially has conflict
or disorder in it certainly has disorder
and then you talk about needing to take
up make a personal decision
to ask yourself why and to ask what's
going to happen and
at the core of it if we're going to
break it all the way all the way down
you have to be a strong person you have
to have
integrity and i don't mean like
following your own morals
as much as just like personal integrity
and
i'm going to tie this together for you
and me right here you got to be
strong and i don't just mean a mind of
the body
right so like guys a lot of my guy my
audience are men we're interested in
masculine issues
and personal sovereignty start with
yourself
start with your body start with your
core start with your squats i like i
tell guys
you gotta squat to save the world and
it's not
an exaggeration man it's like a simple
guide it's like
start with your personal strength squats
are a great way to start
start with your squats to save the world
and it will be through that that we can
develop in personal integrity of
self so that we can be strong
sensemakers
so we can have personal sovereignty
which will hopefully then in turn
lead to a national sovereignty that we
can live with and appreciate
and that can be respected by other
nations and we can respect theirs
as well and so i like to tie it all
together it really is
a a common theme that you can
extrapolate out from
weak soft recipients of information
compared to
strong firm people who are actively
intentionally understanding the world
and i think that guys like you and me
and guys in our square you know part of
the world we are on this side over here
strong firm intentionally understanding
the world
seeking personal sovereignty sovereignty
for everybody
because if you go the other path we know
what happens
everything i think this is in bloom's
book as well when
everything becomes everything nothing is
anything
there's no definitions anymore we have
no identities anymore and that's a
crisis
for existence and so guys
get in this weight room squat your way
to saving the world
i know dave has done that i'm doing it
myself
right next to my studio right here is my
squat rack it's that important to me
yeah so dave thank you so much for
coming on the show man yeah do you have
anything you wanted to say in closing
there i'd look at
no no i i just want to agree with you
completely and um
you know and and at the end at the end
of the day
you want to you know you want to have
your [ __ ] together
yeah um you know if you even want to
remotely start thinking about these
things and yeah i know i mean it's it's
um
it's it's it's a lot to take on and
nobody's perfect nobody has their [ __ ]
together
at all times um but
because you don't it's not an ex you
know it's it
you know because you falter it's not an
excuse to have highs
that to to abandon your standards indeed
and
you know and and that's the important
thing and also
i mean in this in this thing you talk a
lot about you know the import
the importance of of a kind of um
uh a kind of you know brotherhood of
you know people who respect one another
and uh and this
i can't tell you how important that is
i don't think there's anything more
important you know it's it's not
matter it's not some pokey matter of of
uh of
it takes a village but
there's you know there's nothing as as
that is i mean
this is a thing that you know the
ancient greeks knew and that you know
the um you know bloom understood and a
lot of these other guys
and and it's understood by people who've
served in combat together there's
nothing like
having a you know solid group of
friends who you know will have your back
and who will do anything for you
and uh and uh it's it's
just that collaborative thing is so
important i mean it's one of the things
also that i
that i bring from from you know the jazz
world that um
that um that i also loved about andrew
breitbart
was the you know the big thing that
andrew used to do
is he had this jazz impresario's way
of of putting people together and saying
hey
what would happen if i put you and you
and you together
and it was it it was kind of amazing i
mean i would get calls from him at two
or three o'clock in the morning
you know he's somewhere in l.a at a bar
and he's like i just met
you know here talk to so and so and he
would just put so-and-so on the phone
and um you know and and sometimes it was
a hit
and sometimes it was a mess but i mean i
can tell you that
the people who um the people who work
together in those days
under andrew um you know
most of us still know and love one
another in a way that
uh you know
you know in in a way that you know sort
of cannot be cannot be
uh described so um
so that's you know just just a word
about the importance of
you know friendship i appreciate that
guys brotherhood
masculinity personal sovereignty these
are the three core values of the liminal
order and everything we do every day
is work towards improving those in all
the lives of our members so if you're
interested in that come down check it
out
liminal hyphen order dot com uh i am
jack murphy you can find me on twitter
at jack murphy live
instagram facebook youtube jack murphy
live just like i planned it
dave or boy you can find him at dave
roboy on twitter please go follow him
david thank you so much for coming on
today and thank you for talking to me i
really truly appreciate it
it's been wonderful and i can't wait
until florida comes off the gc
quarantine list because i'll be down
there in florida
again all right fantastic thanks for
thanks a [ __ ]
thanks a bunch and uh hang tight right
right here at the end thanks everybody
it's jack murphy live